

CONTACT

(321) 362 8084

pscale01@gmail.com

://ptrc.io/computery

@patreeceeo

PROFILE

Though my recent experience is primarily in frontend engineering, I'm interested in developing adjacent skills such as backend engineering and design, in which I already have some experience. Interested in companies playing an infinite game.

SKILLS +42 more

PATRICK L CANFIELD

T-shaped software engineer

EDUCATION

BS Computer Science

University of North Florida // 2009

Honors Graduate, Varsity athlete cross country and track

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Co-founder / UI Engineer / Designer

EventRay // San Francisco // November 2016 - February 2018

Highlights: Designed and implemented a predicate logic-based automation UI for our end-users, along with an online user manual. Created framework for quickly implementing CRUD UIs. Entire UI was created to work equally well on mobile and desktop. Used React, SASS, Jest etc.

Senior Frontend Engineer

Metromile // San Francisco // March 2016 - November 2016 Implemented "blur up" image technique. Wrote code enabling rapid prototyping of Angular components. Implemented "recent trips" UI, which allows members to play back trips taken in their car, using Mapbox.

Frontend Engineer

GoGet.fit // Various Locations // January 2015 - September 2015

Remote contract role in which I helped choose tools and establish best practices. Also helped design the HTTP API for their mobile app along with writing well-tested lonic and Angular code.

Frontend Engineer

Dozmia // San Francisco // November 2014

Remote contract role in which I laid the foundations for a music streaming startup's web UI, including a splash page employing a masonry effect with randomized album art. Used Backbone.js, primarily.

PATRICK L CANFIELD

INTERESTS

Visual art + Interactions of science, technology and society + Philosophy of mind + Easter philosophy + meditation + Bicycle touring + Environmental protection + Poetry + Culinary art + Music

MORE EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer

Synack // Redwood City // May 2014 - October 2014

Rapidly implemented UIs using Backbone.js

Frontend Engineer

Constant Contact // San Francisco // May 2013 - May 2014

Fellow engineers praised my coding style for being easy to understand and extend. Implemented a UI for scheduling social media posts using Moment.js, Backbone.js and Mustache. Implemented UI components for a new version of their publication authoring platform.

Co-founder / Engineer / Designer

EventRay // Santiago, CL // March 2012 - February 2013

A startup venture that served as a crash course in web development, design and business. And crash we did!

Software Developer

Adtec Digital // Jacksonville, FL // April 2008 - November 2011 Implemented firmware for embedded systems using GNU C++, SQLite and Linux

REFERENCES

John Anderson :: Founder & CEO @ EventRay (954) 854-4398

Matt Stein :: Former Product Manager @ Metromile (415) 250-8252

Bryan Potz :: Engineer @ GoGet.fit (905) 516-8384

Mike Davis :: Former Sr. FE Engineer @ Constant Contact (810) 624-0316